Daniel Camba Lamas

C++ and 3D Graphics Software Engineer

🔗 cambalamas.com 🖾 hello@cambalamas.com 📍 Ourense, Spain 📮 Native 🗯 B1 🚔 B

ABOUT ME

I am a passionate Software Engineer with experience building tools and applications focused on the final user. This includes a 3D training environment, low-level tasks around OpenGL, multi-threading and memory management as well as RESTful APIs, token-based authentication, licensing systems and vanilla frontend.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer 09/2019 - Present

Development of management applications for small businesses in my hometown, learning to deal firsthand with the client and their needs.

R&D Engineer 06/2018 - 07/2019

Polytechnical university of Madrid – Bioengineering Group

- Maintenance of side and legacy C++ projects fixing memory-leaks, minor bugs, addition of multi-threading and C++17 features.
- Co-developer of a 3D training env, built on Unity 3D for the creation, edition and simulation of minimally invasive surgery tasks.
- Lead developer on the migration from a monolithic to a RESTful API system, saving in 75% the code to maintain with a common interface for database operations with user-auth and licensing system.

Backend Engineer 01/2017 - 04/2017

Profocus Estudio - Ecommerce Photography Studio

Workflow improvement, from product reception to the invoicing stage, reducing one-week tasks to two-day tasks. Saving time and resources.

PROJECTS

MSc and Personal projects: (Videos and code on my portfolio)

- **CATCHED**: A non-interactive game to explore AI based on decision trees with safe areas, targets and power-ups.
- **GRIMOIRE**: Interactive Hack&Slash game with melee and range combat; crowd management, waves and difficulty grading.
- **WATERCOLOR:** Draw 3D as watercolor using deferred shading, many perlin noises, toon-shading and implementing hand-wobble.
- **PROCEDURAL TERRAIN:** Using patches for tessellation shaders, perlin for random height map and L.O.D. based on camera distance.
- **CONV FILTERS:** Apply post-processing masks to 3D scene.
- 2D IK: Solvig Jacobian matrices to get inverse kinematic of a 2D arm.

MSc Thesis: Interactive Motion Graph

From scratch 3D interactive animator that load real motion-capture data and computes interpolations between different animations.

BSc Thesis: Interactive mockup definition

Allows you to prototype the behaviour of an application using mockups for a better customer's understanding of the final product.

SKILLS

C++17, 3D Maths, OpenGL, Shaders, GLFW, HTML, CSS, JS, SQL, REST APIs

Multi-threading, memory-management, Unity, Python 3.x, Go.

CUDA, TDD, Docker, Qt, Vulkan, NoSQL, Arduino.

TOOLS

Catch2, Valgrind, GDB, Plotly.

EDUCATION

2017 - 2019

MSc Computer Graphics

OpenGL, CUDA, 3D Maths

University Rey Juan Carlos Madrid, Spain

2012 - 2017

BSc Computer Science

Patterns, Algorithms, UI/UX University of Vigo

HOBBIES

CrossFit Cooking Photography